export const quizData = {
    title: 'General Knowledge Quiz',
    description: 'Test your knowledge with these general knowledge questions!',
    questions : [
      { 
      question: '1. If x^2 +y^2=25 is the equation of circle with center (0,0) what is its radius?',
      options: ['5', '25', '1/5', '5/2 '],
      answer: '5'
      },
      { 
      question: '2. Find the center of the circle with the equation x^2+y^2-2x+4y+39=0    ',
      options: ['1,2', ' -1,-2', '-1,2 ', '1,-2 '],
      answer: '1,-2'
      },
      { 
      question: '3. The equation of circle with radius r and passes through the origin  (0,0) is ',
      options: ['x^2-y^2-r^2=0 ', 'x^2+y^2+r^2=0 ', 'x^2+y^2=r^2', 'x+y=r '],
      answer: 'x^2+y^2=r^2'
      },
      { 
      question: '4. A ____ is a locus of points, equidistant from a given point, called the focus, and from a given line called the directrix   ',
      options: ['Circle ', 'Parabola', ' Ellipse', ' Hyperbola'],
      answer: 'Parabola'
      },
      { 
      question: '5.  If A is  ( -3,2) and B IS  (4,-6 ) the coordinates of the midpoint of AB will be ',
      options: [' 1,2', '-1/2,2 ', '1/2,-2', '-1/2,-2 '],
      answer: '1/2,-2'
      },
      { 
      question: '6. Find the distance between the points (3,-2) and (-4,5)  ',
      options: ['2√7 ', ' 3√2 ', '7√2', ' 7 '],
      answer: '7√2'
      },
      { 
      question: '7.  P divide the line AB,A(-1,2) and B(3,4) internally in ratio of 3,2. Find their coordinates. ',
      options: ['-7/5,-16/5 ', '7/5,-16/5 ', '7/5,16/5', '-7/5,16/5 '],
      answer: '7/5,16/5'
      },
      { 
      question: '8.  Find the gradient of the line joining (3,-2) and (-5,-8)  ',
      options: ['3/4', '-5/4 ', '-5 ', '-3/4 '],
      answer: '3/4'
      },
      { 
      question: '9.  A straight line has a gradient of -3/2 and passes through the point (1,4) . find the equation of the line ',
      options: ['y=-3/2x-11/2 ', ' y=3/2x+11/2 ', 'y=-3/2x+11/2', ' y=3/2x-11/2 '],
      answer: 'y=-3/2x+11/2'
      },
      { 
      question: '10 What is the gradient and y intercept of the line 4x-2y=6  ',
      options: [' gradient=-2 and y intercept=-3 ', 'gradient=2 and y intercept=3', 'gradient=-2 and y intercept=3 ', ' gradient=2 and y intercept=-3'],
      answer: 'gradient=2 and y intercept=-3'
      },
      { 
      question: '11. Find the equation of the line through the point (-1,3) which is parallel to y=3x+1  ',
      options: [' y=3x-6 ', 'y=3x+6', 'y=-3x-6 ', ' y=-3x+6 '],
      answer: 'y=3x+6'
      },
      { 
      question: '12.  What is the directrix of the parabola y^2=16x ',
      options: ['x=4 ', 'x=16 ', 'x=-4', ' y=4√x'],
      answer: 'x=-4'
      },
      { 
      question: '13.  Find the equation of tangent to the parabola y^2=12x at the point (3,6) ',
      options: [' y=x-3 ', 'y=-x+3', 'y=-x-3  ', 'y=x+3'],
      answer: 'y=x+3'
      },
      { 
      question: '14. The radius of the equation of circle 2x^2 + 2y^2=a^2 is  ',
      options: ['√a ', '√a/2   ', 'a/2', 'a '],
      answer: 'a/2'
      },
      { 
      question: '15. An _____ is the locus of a point P, moving in a plane such that the sum of its distances from two fixed point F1 and F2 called foci is a constant  ',
      options: [' Circle', 'Hyperbola ', 'Ellipse', 'Parabola '],
      answer: 'Ellipse'
      },
      { 
      question: '16. Find the equation of the line through point (-1,3) which is perpendicular to y=3x-1  ',
      options: [' 3y-x=8 ', ' 3y+x=-8 ', '-3y-x=8 ', '3y+x=8'],
      answer: '3y+x=8'
      },
      { 
      question: '17. The gradient of the line joining the points (p,q) and (q,p) is ',
      options: ['0 ', '1 ', '-1', ' p/q'],
      answer: '-1'
      },
      { 
      question: '18. State the coordinate of the midpoint of the line joining (2a,b) and (a,2b)  ',
      options: ['a,b ', ' a,2b', '3a/2,3b/2', 'a/2,b/2 '],
      answer: '3a/2,3b/2'
      },
      { 
      question: '19. If the equation of circle is (x+1)^2 +(y-2)^2=9 what is its centre and radius ',
      options: ['1,2 and 9 ', '1,-2 and 3 ', '-1,2 and 3', ' -1,2 and 9 '],
      answer: '-1,2 and 3'
      },
      { 
      question: '20. What is the radius of the equation of circle x^2+y^2-2x-6y=15 ',
      options: ['5', ' √5  ', ' 15', '√15   '],
      answer: '5'
      }
      ,
      // { 
      // question: ' Find the equation of the tangent of the circle x^2+y^2-2x+4y=15 at the point (-1,2)  ',
      // options: ['2y=x-5 ', '-2y=x+5 ', ' 2y=x+5 ', '2y=-x+5 '],
      // answer: '2y=x+5'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  The slope of X(2,5) and Y(3,-6) is ',
      // options: [' 11/2', ' -11/2', '1/11 ', '-11 '],
      // answer: '-11'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Calculate the midpoint between A(4,-6) and B(6,8)  ',
      // options: ['5,1 ', '-1,5 ', '1,5 ', '5,1 '],
      // answer: '5,1'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' If two point are given A(2,x) and B(5,6) and the distance AB is 5 find the value of x  ',
      // options: ['-2 ', '2 ', '3 ', '-3 '],
      // answer: '2'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' If the midpoint of two points A and B is (7,2) if A is (x,y) and B (3,5) find the coordinate of A  ',
      // options: ['-11,1 ', '11,-1 ', '-11,-1 ', '-11,1 '],
      // answer: '11,-1'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' If the equation of a circle is x^2+y^2=25 what is the coordinate of the point  ',
      // options: ['none ', '0,0 ', ' 5,0', 'x,y '],
      // answer: '0,0'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' If the circle centre (1,-3) passes through the origin find its equation  ',
      // options: ['x^2+y^2-2x-6y=0 ', ' x^2+y^2+2x+6y=0 ', ' x^2=y^2-2x+6y=0 ', 'x^2+y^2+2x-6y=0'],
      // answer: 'x^2=y^2-2x+6y=0'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Find the length of the radius if the circle with centre (-3,-4) passes through the point(2,-1) ',
      // options: ['34   ', '√3   ', '√34 ', '3   '],
      // answer: '√34'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  Find the center of the circle with the equation x^2+y^2+x+4y-2=0 ',
      // options: [' ½,2 ', ' 1/2,-2 ', '1/2,-2 ', '-1/2,2 '],
      // answer: '1/2,-2'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Find the focus of the parabola y^2=16x  ',
      // options: ['0,4 ', '-4,0 ', ' 0,-4', '4,0 '],
      // answer: '4,0'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  A _____ is the locus of a point P, moving in a plane such that its distance from two fixed points called foci have a constant difference ',
      // options: [' Circle', 'Ellipse ', 'Parabola ', 'Hyperbola '],
      // answer: 'Hyperbola'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  Find the equation of tangent to the parabola y^2=12x at the point (3,6) ',
      // options: ['y=x-3  ', ' y=-x-3 ', 'y=x+3 ', 'y=-x+3 '],
      // answer: 'y=x+3'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  Find the equation of normal to the parabola y^2=16x at the point (1,-4) ',
      // options: [' 2y+x-9=0 ', 'y+2x=9=0  ', '2y-x+9=0   ', 'y-2x+9=0 '],
      // answer: '2y-x+9=0   '
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  What is the center of the circle with the equation 4x^2+4y^2-12x-8y=9=0 ',
      // options: [' -3/2,1 ', '3/2,1 ', '3/2,-1 ', ' -3/2,-1 '],
      // answer: '3/2,1'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' A straight line has a gradient of 3 and passes through the point (4,2) find its equation of the line  ',
      // options: [' y=3x+10  ', ' y=3x-10  ', 'y=-3x-10   ', ' y=-3x+10  '],
      // answer: 'y=3x-10  '
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Find the equation of line AB which passes through the points A(1,-1) and B(-2,-13)   ',
      // options: ['y=4x+5   ', ' y=-4x-5  ', 'y=4x-5   ', ' y=-4x+5  '],
      // answer: 'y=4x-5  '
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' What is the tangent of angle between the lines x+4y=12 and y-2x+6=0  ',
      // options: ['-9/2 ', ' 9/2', '9/4 ', '1/2 '],
      // answer: '9/2'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' If the lines are perpendicular which of the options is correct for  the two line of gradients m1 and m2  ',
      // options: ['m1=m2 ', 'm1m2=1  ', ' m1m2=-1 ', 'm1=-m2 '],
      // answer: 'm1m2=-1'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' If the lines are parallel which of the options is correct for the two line of gradients m1 and m2  ',
      // options: ['m1 =m2 ', 'm1m2=1 ', 'm1m2=-1 ', 'm1=-m2 '],
      // answer: 'm1=m2'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  Find the gradients of the lines joining the points (p,p^2) and (q,q^2)  ',
      // options: ['q+p ', 'q-p ', 'p-q ', 'q/p '],
      // answer: 'q+p'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Find the distance between the points (a,0) and (0,a)  ',
      // options: ['0 ', 'a ', '√a ', 'a√2 '],
      // answer: 'a√2'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' If P divides BC in ratio of 2:1 and if the  coordinate of B is (-1,-1) and C is (3,-2) find the coordinate of point P  ',
      // options: [' 5/3,5/3', '-5/3,5/3 ', '-5/3,-5/3 ', '5/3,-5/3 '],
      // answer: '5/3,-5/3'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  What is the radius of the circle with equation x^2+y^2=121 ',
      // options: ['121   ', '11 ', '11^2 ', '121^2 '],
      // answer: '11'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Find the equation of line which passes through the point (2,1) with gradient 3  ',
      // options: ['y=3x+5 ', ' y=3x-5 ', 'y=-3x+5 ', 'y=-3x-5 '],
      // answer: 'y=3x-5'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' If the gradient of point (2,5) and (x,7) is 4 what is the value of y  ',
      // options: ['10 ', '=10 ', '12 ', '-12 '],
      // answer: '10'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: 'The equation of the tangent to y^2=20x at (5,10) is   ',
      // options: ['y=x-5 ', 'y=x+5 ', 'y=-x-5 ', 'y=-x+5 '],
      // answer: 'y=x+5'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' The equation of the normal to y^2=20x at (5,10) is  ',
      // options: ['y=x-5 ', 'y=x-15 ', 'y=-x+15 ', 'y=-x-5 '],
      // answer: 'y=-x+15'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' What is the focus and directrix of the parabola y^2=40x  ',
      // options: ['0,10 and 10 ', '0,10 and -10 ', '10,0 and -10 ', '10,10 and 10 '],
      // answer: '10,0 and -10'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' If the directrix of the parabola is x=-5 what is its equation  ',
      // options: ['y^2=-20x ', 'y^2=5x ', ' y^2=-5x ', ' y^2=20x '],
      // answer: 'y^2=20x'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  Find the midpoint of the points (1,3) and (5,3)  ',
      // options: ['-2,0 ', '-3,-3 ', '2,0 ', '3,3 '],
      // answer: '3,3'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  Find the equation of the line through (2,-1) which is perpendicular to the line 5y-10x=9 ',
      // options: ['2y=-x ', ' -2y=x ', '2y=x ', ' y=-x '],
      // answer: '2y=-x'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Find the tangent of the angle between the lines, y=2x-9 & 2y=7x+4 ',
      // options: ['16/3 ', '3/16 ', '5/4 ', '5/3 '],
      // answer: '3,16'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '  Find the equation of the line through(2,3) if the slope of the line is 6. ',
      // options: ['y=5x+14  ', 'y=5x-14  ', 'y=6x+15  ', 'y=6x-15   '],
      // answer: 'y=6x+15  '
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Find the equation of the line through (2,3) which is perpendicular to the line 3y+4x-4=0  ',
      // options: ['Y=3x/5+3/2 ', 'y=3x/4 + 3/2 ', ' y=-3x/4 - 3/2 ', ' y=-3x/4 + 3/2 '],
      // answer: 'y=3x/4 + 3/2'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' The eccentricity of hyperbola is  ',
      // options: ['e>1 ', ' e=1', 'e<1 ', 'e=0 '],
      // answer: 'e>1'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Find the vertex of the parabola y²=12x ',
      // options: ['0,0 ', ' 0,1', '1,0 ', '1,1 '],
      // answer: '0,0'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' x1 + y1 = r² is the equation of tangent to a _______ when passing through the origin.  ',
      // options: ['Circle ', 'Ellipse ', 'Rectangle ','square '],
      // answer: 'Circle'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: '_____ is a set of all points in a plane that are equivalent from a fixed point ',
      // options: ['Circle ', 'Rectangle ', ' Square', ' Triangle'],
      // answer: 'Circle'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Find the focus of the parabola y²=12x  ',
      // options: ['3,0 ', '4,0 ', '0,3 ', '0,4 '],
      // answer: '3,0'
      // },
      // { 
      // question: ' Find the equation of the tangent to a circle x²+y²-2y+6x-7=0 at point(-2,3)  ',
      // options: [' x+2y-16=0 ', 'x+y-16=0  ', '2y-16=0  ', 'x+-16=0  '],
      // answer: 'x+2y-16=0'
      // },
      ]
      
      
  };
  